2nd Floor, 13 Baggot St Upper, Dublin 4, D04 W7K5

W: www.shamrockassist.com E: info@shamrockassist.com P: 01-6854700 & 01-6994321

Fax: 01-6852538



SRA Locum Template

It is of importance that all our CVs are received in the same format. We appreciate if you could fill this template out and return to info@sralocum.com. Should you have any questions please contact: Shahid Ali, Locum Coordination Consultant, SRA Locum (00353 1 685 4700).

DR. FARAH DEEBA KAMAL Irish Medical Council License: 429738

Address: 38 Glentaun Close, Ballinasloe, Co. Galway. H53 XY49

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Professional Summary

Accomplished general practitioner with 6 years of experience in the medical field. Highly skilled in diagnosing and treating a variety of human diseases and injuries. Exceptional understanding of drug properties and interactions, procedural techniques, and preventative health-care methods. Ability to provide psychological diagnosis, treatment, and rehabilitation for patients with mental and physical dysfunctions. Extraordinary decision-making skills and critical thinking capabilities.

Skills

– Excellent critical thinking and problem-solving skills when identifying the best treatment option for various injuries and ailments. – Superior reading comprehension skills and effective written and oral communication skills. – In-depth knowledge of procedures for diagnosing and treating patients. – Understanding of mental and physical rehabilitation methods and counseling approaches. – Exceptional interpersonal skills and personable bedside manner. – Ability to plainly explain physical problems as well as treatment solutions so patients have a clear understanding of what is happening to their bodies and how treatment can help them. – Outstanding perception skills that allow me to sense the emotions of my patients and help them feel at ease.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

<u>Date</u>	<u>Grade</u>	<u>Area</u>
5 th Feb 2023	<u>Medical SHO</u>	<u>Midland Regional Hospital Tullamore</u>

2nd Floor, 13 Baggot St Upper,

<u>Dublin 4, D04 W7K5</u>

W: www.shamrockassist.com E: info@shamrockassist.com

P: 01-6854700 & 01-6994321

Fax: 01-6852538



<u>12th Feb 2023</u>	ED Registrar	Midland Regional Hospital Tullamore

Jinnah Post Graduate Medical Centre

July 2012 to July2013

House Officer/Internship

- 6 months House Job/Internship in the Department of Surgery Rotation 09-july-2012 to 09-jan2013
- 6 months House Job/Internship in the Department of Medicine Rotation 15-jan-2013 to 14-jul-2013

Shamsi Hospital (Karachi, Pakistan):

AUG-2013 to Aug- 2015

Worked in Emergency Department as "Registered Medical Officer" (RMO)

- Administer treatment, medication, therapy, vaccinations, and other medical care to treat patient
- Prescribe medication or specialized care to meet specific patient needs.
- Monitor the progress and current condition of patients to determine whether current treatments are working or if modifications are needed.
- Collect patient information (including examination results, medical history, and other reports). Record information in electronic filing systems.
- Explain test results and recommended procedures to patients.
- •Analyze images or test data to make diagnoses and develop treatment plans.

Ministry of Health, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia (Eastern Province): Nov-2015 to Nov-2016

Worked in Emergency Department as an "Emergency Resident/ General Physician".

• Access health status of patients through history taking, physical.

2nd Floor, 13 Baggot St Upper, Dublin 4, D04 W7K5

W: www.shamrockassist.com

E: info@shamrockassist.com

P: 01-6854700 & 01-6994321

Fax: 01-6852538



- Monitored patients during prenatal and postnatal periods and performed tests and prescribed medications as necessary.
- Collect, record, and maintain patient information, such as medical history, reports, and examination results.
- Monitor patients' conditions and progress and reevaluate treatments as necessary.
- Answer patient questions and use active listening skills to understand and address concerns.
- Provide emotional support and medical attention to others as needed, including patients, customers, and coworkers.
- Analyze images or test data to make diagnoses and develop treatment plans.
- Health education and counseling to the patients with chronic diseases.
- Referred patients to specialties and to patient care components as appropriate.

Health Services Program of Royal Commission Hospital in Jubail, Saudi Arabia: 03-July-2017 to 21-Jan-2021

Worked in Cardiology as an "Medical Officer/General Physician"

- Managing acute cardiovascular medical emergencies in ER and inpatient cases like angina
 pectoris, coronary heart disease, atherosclerosis, myocardial Infarction (STEMI or N-STEMI),
 cardiac arrhythmias, acute or chronic heart failure and valvular heart disease.
- Evaluation and treatment of adults with acute and chronic cardiovascular conditions in the outpatient setting utilizing evidence-based medicine with an emphasis in the area of heart failure.
- Extensive experience in the diagnosis and treatment of a wide range of cardiovascular conditions, such as angina pectoris, coronary heart disease, atherosclerosis, myocardial infarction, and several other disorders of the cardiovascular system
- Pre-procedural history and physical examination
- Implemented comprehensive care plans for the full recovery of patient health
- Case presentation in the daily morning rounds and grand round weekly

Portiuncula University Hospital, Ballinasloe 18-Jan-2021 till now:

Working in Emergency as an "Registrar"

- Facilitate patient care in ER and Urgent Care, consulting with other medical practitioners to diagnose diseases and identify structural and functional changes to body tissue, fluids, secretions, and other specimens.
- Evaluate the presence and stage of diseases, utilizing laboratory procedures if necessary.
- Evaluate the presence and stage of diseases, utilizing laboratory procedures if necessary.
- Work in a team environment, communicating and corresponding with nurses, occupational therapists, and social workers, resulting in the discharge planning of patients.



2nd Floor, 13 Baggot St Upper,

Dublin 4, D04 W7K5

W: www.shamrockassist.com

E: info@shamrockassist.com

P: 01-6854700 & 01-6994321

Fax: 01-6852538



- Effectively communicate with patients and family members using clarity; update medical progress and develop discharge plans.
- Provided patients and their families with the information, guidance, and direction needed to maximize the outcomes of their medical care.
- Performed thorough clinical assessments, diagnosing patients and formulating treatment plans.

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION

<u>Matriculation:</u> from <u>SHAMSI SOCIETY SCHOOL</u> (Karachi Board) in 2004 with <u>87% Marks.</u> <u>Intermediate:</u> F.Sc. Pre-Medical from <u>PECHS Govt. Girls College</u> (Karachi Board) in 2006 with 80% Marks.

M.B.B.S: from DOW UNIVERSITY OF HEALTH AND SCIENCES Karachi, Pakistan in 2012.

Professional License:

Pakistan Medical & Dental Council License: 61909-S

Saudi Medical License: 16-A-M-0019050 Irish Medical Council License: 429738

PERSONAL DETAIL

Date of birth 19th JANUARY 1987

Place of birth
 Nationality
 Passport no.
 Gender
 Marital Status:
 KARACHI
 PAKISTANI
 AL4203982
 FEMALE
 Married

• Language ENGLISH, ARABIC, URDU